<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Rhea Kara</title>
    <link>https://www.rheakara.com/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Rhea Kara</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Your Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 17:05:15 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.rheakara.com/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://www.rheakara.com/blog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 17:05:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rheakara.com/blog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For some background, I was previously using Squarespace to host an equivalent
personal site. It started with the very good intentions of making (semi-)regular
blog posts on whatever caught my interests and to also have a place serving as
a portfolio / contact. Squarespace at the time fit the needs of my unjustified urgency
to have something up and running, and just like that, I was a member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignoring the fact that I barely, if at all, used the site, there were two major
points that bothered me greatly. In particular:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paying $16/month for a very low traffic website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not having reliable backup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some recent circumstantial changes, I finally found myself with much more
time and decided to finally move off of Squarespace. I eventually settled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; after some research as a nice solution to these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paying-0-month-for-a-insert-here-traffic-website&#34;&gt;Paying $0/month for a (insert here) traffic website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially I considered moving over to &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/WebsiteHosting.html&#34;&gt;AWS S3&lt;/a&gt;
as it is a familiar part of my
recent past, present, and (likely) near future. However what steered me away from
this was the discovery of &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; which offers
free static website hosting. Thankfully I &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RTFM&#34;&gt;RTFM&amp;rsquo;d&lt;/a&gt;
as spending time on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;Hugo&amp;rsquo;s docs&lt;/a&gt;
quickly pointed me in the direction of this hosting option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast to AWS S3, Github Pages offers free hosting for static websites. Given
that I don&amp;rsquo;t expect things to be very high traffic, it at most it saves me literally
&amp;ldquo;pennies&amp;rdquo; vs AWS S3 as I estimate the latter would have cost me something like a nickel
a month. But then again I&amp;rsquo;m already I&amp;rsquo;m on a roll at cutting expenditures so why not just eek out the rest of the marginal returns right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But seriously, what really reeled me in was that I&amp;rsquo;d already planned to use Git so it was
just too convenient of a choice not to go with. As for the reason why I wanted to use
Git, it was because it would serve as both a VCS and my potential backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;having-a-reliable-backup&#34;&gt;Having a reliable backup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Git to keep track of my changes allows me to easily have a copy of all
past states of my blog. If for some reason I impetuously decided to delete a bunch
of posts or change my layouts dramatically only to regret it the next day, no
problem. It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as reverting those changes to get back everything I want. So
using Git (or any VCS), something I would be unable to do so using
Squarespace, essentially allows me to have a backup of all publications of my
website for any point in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t ignored AWS S3 completely as I store a compressed backup there. According to
their FAQ:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/faqs/#data-protection&#34;&gt;if you store 10,000 objects with Amazon S3, you can on average expect to incur a loss of a single object once every 10,000,000 years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which makes it really nice to have around either way even if I am not using it as
a hosting service, and instead just as a compressed dump store instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the move I no longer have that nagging voice in my head about &amp;ldquo;that one&amp;rdquo;
unnecessary expenditure. I also now have a very durable backup(s) of my site, so
I rest much more at ease at knowing I likely won&amp;rsquo;t lose anything or be held hostage
for this data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those interested, everything related to this blog can be found in these
two repositories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ryaka/rheakara&#34;&gt;Website content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ryaka/mila&#34;&gt;Hugo theme used&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I warn you there isn&amp;rsquo;t really any documentation(at the time of this writing) but
I do intent to add them. Feel free to use the theme if you&amp;rsquo;d like however I don&amp;rsquo;t
have any plans to offer support or promises against breaking changes as I&amp;rsquo;m making
changes to fit my needs as they arise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>